Our history view is now looking pretty good and if you remember,
History 视图现在看起来很棒了
we also have our AddEntry view,
还有一个 AddEntry 视图
which is also looking pretty good.
看起来也很不错
We can't really go much further in our app without adding navigation.
如果不添加导航功能的话 我们的应用就无法继续完善了
The very first thing we need to do is head over to
首先 我们需要转到终端
your terminal and yarn add re-act navigation.
运行 yarn add react-navigation
Once that's done, go ahead and restart your app and head back over to your App.js file.
运行完毕后 重启应用 并回到 App.js 文件
What we're going to do here is,
在此文件中
let's first grab platform because we'll need that for some styling and then go ahead and
首先导入 Platform 因为我们需要用它来进行样式设置
grab the TabNavigator off of react-navigation and then while we are here,
然后从 react-navigation 中导入 TabNavigator
let's go ahead and grab a few colors,
趁机导入一些颜色
purple and white from
从 utils/colors 导入 purple 和 white
util/colors and then we're also going to need to specify the specific icons,
然后我们还需要添加
which are going to be on the tabs that we're about to build.
在即将构建的标签页中显示的具体图标
What we'll use is Fontawesome as well as Ionicons.
我们将使用 FontAwesome 和 Ionicons
All right. Now what we want to do,
现在
is we want to actually create our tabs component so the way we can do that,
我们将创建 Tabs 组件
is we can invoke TabNavigator and
我们可以调用 TabNavigator
the first object we are going to pass it
我们要传入的第一个对象
is going to represent the tabs that we want to see on the screen.
将代表我们想在屏幕上看到的标签页
We will have history,
输入 History
the screen we're going to render is our history component and let's go
我们要渲染的屏幕是 History 组件
ahead and give it some navigation options, the tabBarLabel.
我们添加一些 navigationOptions 和 tabBarLabel
What it's going to show on the tab bar,
它将在标签栏上显示“History”
is it will say history and then the tabBarIcon is going to be a function,
tabBarIcon 将是一个函数
which is going to take in a tintColor,
向其传入 tintColor
which we will set here in a minute and we want to render this icon,
稍后设置该 tintColor 我们还要渲染这个图标
which is why we imported it,
因此导入它
the name we will say is iOS bookmarks.
name 设为 ios-bookmarks
Size, we'll set it equal to 30,
size 设为 30
and then the color is going to be this tintColor so we have a history tab.
color 设为这个 tintColor；History 标签页设置好了
Now we also need
现在还需要设置 AddEntry 标签页
our AddEntry tab because that was the other component that we built as well.
因为这是我们构建的另一个组件
Similar, the screen is going to be AddEntry.
类似地 screen 将为 AddEntry
We're going to have some navigation options,
添加一些 navigationOptions
tabBarLabel is going to be AddEntry and then the tabBarIcon is going to be a function,
tabBarLabel 将为 Add Entry tabBarIcon 将为一个函数
which also accepts the tintColor and is going to render a Fontawesome icon,
同样接受 tintColor 它将渲染一个 FontAwesome 图标
with the name of plus square,
name 为 plus-square
the size of 30 and the color is going to be tintColor.
size 为 30 color 为 tintColor
All right. These are
这些就是我们的标签页
our tabs and now what we want to do is we want to specify some options for these tabs.
现在我们想为这些标签页指定一些选项
Specifically, things like how they look and whatnot.
具体包括外观等
What we'll do is as the second argument to TabNavigator,
我们将向 TabNavigator 传入一个对象作为第二个参数
we will pass it an object and we will say tabBarOptions.
称之为 tabBarOptions
It's going to have an active tintColor so this is going to
为其设置 activeTintColor
be the color of the selected tab.
它将为所选标签页的颜色
What we want to do here is we will say,
在此处输入代码
if we're on iOS,
如果我们位于 iOS 上
then this is going to be purple and if we're not then
则为 purple 如果不是
it's going to be white and you'll see why we're doing that here in a second.
则为 white 稍后你就会明白为何这么设置
Then now what we want to do is under tabBarOptions as well,
然后 在 tabBarOptions 中
we want to have some styling that we're going to apply to the tab bar.
我们将添加一些要应用到标签栏上的样式
We will give it a height of 56, background color.
height 为 56；对于 backgroundColor
Again, if we're on iOS,
如果位于 iOS 上
we want it to be white and if we're not,
则为 white
then we want it to be purple and then let's go ahead and give us some shadow.
如果不是 则为 purple；然后设置一些阴影
I'm just going to paste this in so what we've done is we have a shadowColor,
我直接粘贴这些代码 我们设置了 shadowColor
shadowOffset, shadowRadius and shadowOpacity.
shadowOffset、shadowRadius 和 shadowOpacity
I believe that looks pretty good.
我认为看起来很不错
Now, what we have is,
现在 Tabs 是一个组件
tab's as a component because that's what TabNavigator returns us.
因为 TabNavigator 返回的就是一个组件
What we can actually do here is instead of
因此 在此处
rendering history or instead of rendering AddEntry here,
我们不再像之前那样渲染 History 或 AddEntry
as we did earlier, we can just render tabs.
而是可以渲染 Tabs
If everything is working right,
如果一切正常的话
you'll see here, that we now have these tabs.
你会在这里看到这些标签页
What's nice here is Android has its own styling and so does iOS.
比较棒的是 Android 具有自己的样式 iOS 亦如此
Now, we can navigate between these two and one thing I want to add real quick.
现在我们可以在这两个标签页之间导航
That won't affect us in this video but it'll affect us in the future,
现在我要快速添加一项内容 这项内容不会在此视频中影响到我们 但是在未来会有作用
is up here inside of our kind of options object.
我将在这个对象中
What I want to do is say navigationOptions,
输入 navigationOptions
headers are just going to be set to NULL.
将 header 设为 null
This is just going to get rid of any headers
暂时先去掉任何报头
that we will eventually have in our app but we don't have right now.
最终会在应用中设置报头 但是暂时先为空
We'll save that. Again, everything looks good.
保存代码 一切看起来不错
We can now navigate between these two components.
现在 我们可以在这两个组件之间导航了